本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译创作
欢迎爱好者加入我们  www.YYeTs.com
翻译： spriteNT   兔子1M   永不永不苍老 时间轴： 潘叔
校对：小舞 监制：可乐嘻嘻  后期：yyp
我没射中你的心脏
I just missed your heart.
汉娜
你现在已经死了
You are dead, right now.
我杀了你
I've killed you.
徒手打
Use your hands.
自己把鹿拖回去
Drag the deer back yourself.
怎么了
What's wrong?
受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
迷迷糊糊的样子
You were half asleep.
你得随时准备好
You must always be ready.
即便是在睡觉
Even when you're sleeping.
反应也要迅速敏捷
Think on your feet.
-非生...  -即死
- Adapt... - Or die.
下次我会做得更好
I'll do better next time.
德语
German.
下次我会做得更好
I'll do better next time.
意大利语
Italian.
下次我会做得更好
I'll do better next time.
西班牙语
Spanish.
Espanol.
真要我扭断你脖子吗
Did you really want me to snap your neck?
你把那头鹿分成多少块了
How much did you pull off the deer?
120块
In 120 parts.
共200磅重吧
200 pounds in total.
我想是的
I think so.
这就对了
That explains it.
对什么
What?
你打我的力度
How you beat me.
你更强壮了
You've getting stronger.
很高兴你没把我的脖子扭断
I'm glad you didn't snap my neck.
大蓝鲸是史上最大的动物
The great blue whale is the largest animal to have ever existed.
它的心脏就重达1300磅
Its heart weighs 1300 pounds.
雄性蓝鲸有7加仑大的...
And the male has 7 gallons of...
睾丸
testicles.
500英里外就能听到蓝鲸之乐...
The blue whale's music can be heard for over five hundred miles...
蓝鲸舌头的重量超过2.5吨
A blue whale's tongue weighs over two and a half tons.
音乐什么样子
What does music feel like?
音乐  是声音的组合
Music- a combination of sounds
一种表达美和思想情感的艺术
with a view to beauty of form and expression of emotion.
我想亲耳听听
I want to hear it for myself.
这里一应俱全
We've all we need right here.
还不够
It's not enough.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
爸爸  我准备好了
Papa, I'm ready.
《格林童话》
1  2  3  4  5  6
One, two, three, four, five, six.
我住在德国莱比锡城
I live in Leipzig German city.
人口  70万
Population: 0.7 million peoples.
再说一次
Tell me again.
威廉・格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德国
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
我们住在维琴察广场7号
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
我就读于克劳斯学院文理中学
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
鲁迪・甘特和克莱拉・沙伊茨是我最好的朋友
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
威廉・格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德国
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
我喜欢文学和运动
I like literature and sport.
特别是网球和田径
In particular, tennis and athletics.
我们住在维琴察广场7号
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
我就读于克劳斯学院文理中学
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
鲁迪・甘特和克莱拉・沙伊茨是我最好的朋友
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
我还有一条小狗叫特鲁迪
I also have a dog called Trudy.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我已经准备好了
I'm ready now.
3  4  5  6
Three, four, five, six.
看到了吗  听到了吗
Did you see it? Did you hear it?
就像打雷一样  太美了
It's like thunder! It was so beautiful!
那是什么
What is it?
它能告诉玛丽莎・维格拉我们的方位
It tells Marissa Wiegler where we are.
如果你觉得准备好了  打算离开这里
If you think you're ready, and you want to leave here,
只需打开开关就行
all you have to do is flip that switch.
但一旦触碰开关  就别无退路
But once it's done there's no going back.
除非你死或者她亡  她决不会放弃
She won't stop until you're dead, or she is.
明白了吗
You understand?
我不会替你做决定
I won't be there to hold your hand.
自己考虑清楚
So be sure.
想清楚这是不是你的真正所想
Be sure it's what you really want.
它就在这  不急  要想清楚
It's here. There's no rush.
莱卡是莫斯科街头的一种杂种狗
Laika, a mongrel dog from the street of Moscow,
也是第一只绕地飞行的动物
was the first animal to orbit the Earth.
1957年11月3日  她被送入外太空
She was launched into outer space on the third of November, 1957.
科学家认为人类
Scientists believe humans
无法忍受外太空的环境
would be unable to survive the conditions of outer space.
因此动物的航天飞行就成了
So flights by animals were used
人类探索外太空的先驱实验
as experiments precursory to human missions.
那时的火箭是不可回收式的
A rocket was not designed to be retrievable,
莱卡就是去送命的
and Laika has always been, intended to die.
但她没死  对吗
But she didn't, did she?
还记得吗  他们无法收回火箭
They couldn't bring the rocket back, remember?
记得
I remember.
但有时我希望你能换种方式看问题
But sometimes I wish you would read it differently.
当一颗行星瓦解时
When a star collapses,
超新星爆炸所发出的光
the supernova explosion is ten billion times
要比其他行星要亮百亿倍
brighter than the other stars.
和我一起去打猎吗
Will you hunt with me?
如果你想我陪的话
If you want.
随你吧
Well, it's up to you.
-我吗  -没错
- Me? - Yes.
那我待家里
I'll stay.
好  好吧
Yes, good.
玛丽莎・维格拉
Marissa Wiegler...
来找我吧
come and find me.
你很幸运能猎到那头鹿
You were lucky to have caught that deer.
今天外面什么也没有
There was nothing out there today.
闻着很香
The smell's good.
什么时候能吃
When will it be ready?
就快了
Soon.
我们接收到一个明码信号  是自己人
We've picked up an unencrypted signal. One of ours.
-什么时候  -东部时间6点32分
- When? - 0632 Eastern Standard.
定位北极圈以外60英里附近
Triangulated about 60 miles below the Arctic Circle.
靠近卡祖玛
Near Kazuma.
我们猜是埃里克・海勒
We think it is Erik Heller.
-埃里克・海勒  -他是你负责的吧
- Erik Heller? - You're his handler, right?
对  名字听上去挺熟
Sure, the name sounds familiar.
美利坚合众国
该死的埃里克
Fuck Erik.
为什么是现在
Why now?
看起来怎么样
How does it look?
不错...
Good...
差不多
Almost good.
埃里克・海勒  1991年入伍
Erik Heller, recruited in 1991.
他是正式的FSK特工[通信技术工]
Formal FSK operative.
是我们在东欧和中亚反间谍活动中
He became integral to our counter Intelligence Ops
不可或缺的一员
in Eastern europe and Central Asia.
94年后档案一片空白
His file ends in '94.
1996年4月18日  在约翰娜・祖迪克的尸体边
There was no sign of life until April 18, 1996,
发现一把带有他指纹的22口径鲁格手枪
when his fingerprints were found on a 22 calibre ruger,
鲁格是美国一家世界名枪公司
此前不知其生死情况
found beside body of one, Johanna Zadek.
约翰娜・祖迪克  1970年出生于德国
Johanna Zadek, born in 1970, German.
1994年  海勒发现并发展了她
She was spotted and developed by Heller in 1994.
-从未受雇  -为什么发展她
- Never recruited. - Why was she being developed?
文件中没有记录  继续说过去的事
That's not in the file. Let's keep on the past.
海勒很不安分
Heller is a rogue asset.
我建议我们去把他揪出来
I propose we go and pull him out.
我们还有更重要的问题  玛丽莎
We got bigger problems, Marissa.
让国际刑警去抓吧
Let Interpol pick him up.
他现在不归我们管
He's no longer our responsibility.
国际刑警一逮捕他
Interpol nabs him,
BND  FSB和法国方面就会找到他
that exposes him to BND, FSB, France.
BND  德国联邦情报局
FSB  俄国联邦安全部门
你们真想每个欧洲情报局
Do you really want every intelligence agency
抓住这个祸害吗
in Europe scratching at this threat?
-路易斯  -抱歉
- Lewis? - I'm sorry,
这事还是我们自己来解决  先生们
but we need to keep this contained, gentlemen.
别声张  我与他共过事
Keep it small. I've worked with this man.
他知道些你们不想知道的事
He knows things I don't think you wanna know.
感谢你的坦率
I appreciate your candor.
你有什么需要  路易斯
What do you need Lewis?
抓一个人  给我一天时间
One man, one-day operation.
-再说一次  -玛丽莎・维格拉
- Tell me again. - Marissa Wiegler.
-然后  -明信片
- Then? - Postcard.
-再然后  -什么
- Then? - What?
我们见面的地址
The address where we meet.
威廉・格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm House, Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德国
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
-还有什么  -非生即死
- Then what else? - Adapt or die.
-反应要迅速敏捷  -即便是在睡觉
- Think on your feet... - Even when I'm sleeping.
爸爸
Papa.
记住我教你的  你会没事的
Remember what I taught you and you will be fine.
那里见
I'll see you there.
麦考林  听见吗
Macalahan, do you read me?
麦考林
Macalahan.
麦考林  听见吗
Macalahan, do you read me?
冲  冲  冲
Go, go, go.
埃里克・海勒逃走了
Erik Heller escaped.
怎么跑的
How did that happen?
不清楚  我们认为他趁着暴雪跑了或...
Unclear. We think he got away in the snow storm or...
还有比我想象更严重的事
And something bigger than that I can manage.
抓一个人  只消一天时间
One man, one day of operations.
找到他  路易斯
Just find him, lewis.
把人给我找出来
Find him and bring him to me.
还有个孩子  事情出人意料
There was a kid. Things got out of our control!
维格拉
Wiegler?
维格拉  你在听吗
Wiegler, are you there?
她现在哪里
Where is she now?
你好  汉娜
Hello, Hanna.
你好
Hello.
我是伯顿医生  乐意和我谈谈吗
My name is Dr. Burton. Would you like to talk to me?
爸爸告诉我凡事得先占上风
I was told by my father to gain the upper hand.
很有意思
That's very interesting.
你爸爸还告诉了你什么
What else did your father tell you?
我在哪里
Where am I?
有人守着你
You are in holding.
我从没见过这样的房间
I've never been in a room like this.
这对你来说肯定很怪
Must all be very strange for you.
你在森林里住了多久
How long have you been in the forest?
汉娜
Hanna?
-那些是摄像头吗  -对
- Are those cameras? - Uhuh.
现在它们就在拍摄我们
They're taking our pictures right now,
在做记录
to keep a record.
你有什么感受
How does that make you feel?
隐藏的摄像头...
Camera obscure...
拉丁语中暗室的意思
It's Latin, for dark chamber.
1021年  阿拉伯科学家
It was first described by the Arabic scientist
伊本・海塞姆首次命名了它
Ibn al-Haytham in the year 1021.
把信号传送至兰利
Plug the cctv through to Langley.
兰利  美国中央情报局本部
嘿  你得给她做个全面的精神分析
Hey, you should have a visual on the psych evaluation there.
要我拿点什么给你吗  你喜欢什么
Can I get you something? What do you like?
音乐还是杂志
Music, magazines.
尽管开口  什么都行
Just ask, anything.
我想和玛丽莎・维格拉谈谈
I want to speak to Marissa Wiegler.
-告诉她我今晚就去  -我能处理
- Tell her I'll be there tonight. - I can handle this.
按我说的做
Just do what you're told.
约翰  快看看这孩子的血样
John, take a look at this kid's blood sample.
-没弄错吧  -是吗
- Is that right? - Is it?
-不可能吧  -这是她头发的样本
- Can't be right. - Got a sample of her hair.
肯定污染了  再做一次
Must be contaminated. Run it again.
我是玛丽莎・维格拉
My name is Marissa Wiegler.
你想和我谈谈吗
You wanted to speak with me?
去外面等着我
You can wait outside.
我在哪里
Where am I?
一个安全的地方  宝贝
You are in a safe place, sweetie.
你是在哪里遇见我的爸爸
Where did you meet my father?
埃里克
Erik.
你指埃里克吗
You mean Erik?
是的
Yes.
我是在东柏林亚历山大广场的一个报亭遇见他
I met him by a news kiosk at Alexander Platz. East Berlin.
我在一个报亭遇见了他
I met him at a news kiosk,
-在亚历山大广场...  -下着雨
- Alexander Platz... - Say it was raining.
当时还下着雨
in the rain.
他刚从布格拉回来
He'd just arrived from Prague.
你知道你爸爸在哪里吗
You know where your father is?
他告诉你他去哪里了吗
Did he tell you where he was going?
我们都很担心他
We are worried about him.
没事的
It's okay.
特工  注意保持距离
Agent, keep your distance.
没事的
It's okay.
你要我给她点什么吗
Do you want me to give her something?
我觉得很有必要
I think that might be necessary.
快停止
Abort.
打开
Open up.
我再说一遍  特工  快停止
I repeat, agent, abort!
维格拉
Wiegler!
所有人立刻集合
I want everyone here now.
别让她逃出走廊
Do not let it escape from the gallery.
检验报告
-你说她逃出去了吗  -不可能
- Do you think she got out? - She can't get out.
通知所有部门
Detail every unit available.
已结案
德国护照
妈妈
Mama.
她永远不会是你的
She will never be yours.
嘿  你好
Hey, hello.
你会说英语吗
Don't you speak English?
不会也不是你的错
It's not your fault if you can't.
艾玛・艾克里直到八岁才会说英语
Emma Ackery couldn't speak English until she was eight,
因为那时她就像个来自斯里兰卡的难民
because she was like, a refugee or something from Sri Lanka.
但现在她是个歌星  在美国也很有名
But now she's a pop star, in America too.
所以别担心现在不会说英语
So don't worry if you can't speak English yet.
她是谁
Who's she?
我找到了她  她不会说英语
I found her, she can't speak English.
她来自斯里兰卡
She's from Sri Lanka.
我来自德国
I'm from Germany.
我住在莱比锡城  人口70万
I live in Leipzig. Population: 0.7 million peoples.
我们住在维琴察广场7号
We live at No. 7 Vicenza Platz.
我喜欢文学和运动
I like literature and sport,
特别是网球和田径
in particular tennis and athletics.
我就读于克劳斯学院文理中学
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
鲁迪・甘特和克莱拉・沙伊茨是我最好的朋友
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
听起来蛮有趣
They sound fun.
我还有一条小狗叫特鲁迪
I also have a dog called Trudy.
我们以前有条叫文森特的小狗
We had a dog called Vincent,
但它发疯死了
but he went mad and died.
索菲  快来
Sophie, come on.
再见
See ya.
索菲  快来
Sophie, come on.
我叫索菲  那是我弟弟迈尔斯
I'm Sophie and that is my brother, Miles.
我叫汉娜
I am...Hanna.
要搭便车吗
Do you need a lift somewhere?
不了  我更喜欢走路
No. I prefer to walk.
随你的便
Suit yourself.
索菲  快点  就等你了
Sophie, come on, we are all waiting for you.
监视器显示她在沙漠里
Tacticle says she's in the desert,
在我们的东南方
south east of vessel we're in.
全力追捕海勒
Focus all operations on Heller.
你的意思是这女孩对我们没价值吗
Are you saying the girl's not of interest to us?
她当然有用  路易斯
Yes, of course she's of interest, Lewis.
但她还不会
But not an immediate threat
对美国的安全构成直接威胁
to the security of the United States of America.
埃里克・海勒是眼下最危险的人物  以他为重
Erik Heller is the immediate threat. Focus on Heller.
鲁拜宾馆
你的家人呢
Where is your family?
-你是阿拉伯人吗  -我是摩洛哥人
- Are you Arabic? - I am Moroccan.
摩洛哥  首都是拉巴特
Morocco. Capital city: Rabat.
著名景点包括马拉喀什和索维拉
Places of interest: Marrakech, Essaouira.
信奉伊斯兰教  语种为阿拉伯语
Religion: Islam. Language: Arabic.
我很喜欢阿拉伯语
I like Arabic very much.
像日语一样  是个丰富的语言
It's like Japanese, it's big.
你会说阿拉伯语吗
You speak Arabic?
当然会说
Yes, of course.
你的家人在哪儿
Where is your family?
我今晚要找个地方住
I need a room for the night.
但我没钱  你能帮帮我吗
Can you help? I have no money.
这是我们这儿最好的房间
It's the best we've got.
谢谢
Thank you.
每个房间都有这东西吗
Do you have one of these in every room?
所有的房间都有
All the rooms are the same.
是电
It's electricity.
还用说吗  都是现代化设备
Of course, all mod cons.
我对电知之甚少
I know a little about electricity.
人们说是爱迪生发明了电
They say Edison invented it.
还是富兰克林来着
Or was it Franklin?
反正是个美国人
Some American I'm sure.
这个是电热水壶
This is an electrical kettle.
专为英国人准备的
It's for the English.
他们喜欢自己烧水沏茶
They like to make their own tea.
这是什么
What is it?
有这就够不错的了
It's the best we can do.
你从哪儿来
Where do you come from?
森林
The forest.
是那个德国女孩
It's the German girl.
穿摩洛哥宽长袍的德国佬
It's Kraut in a big Djellaba.
即像雏妓又像拉拉
Like quail or lesbo.
我觉得当个拉拉也挺不错的
I think I'd quite like to be lesbian.
但我的恋人不能太胖  得像模特一样
But not one of those fat ones, one who's like, a supermodel.
但也只是玩玩儿  我应该还是会嫁个男人
But who don't hold hands, and I think I'd probably marry a man.
什么
What?
不亲一个吗
No kiss?
她对你来说有点太老了吧
She's a bit old for you, isn't she?
她是个人妖
She has male and female genetalias.
这就是你为之倾倒的原因吧
And you love her just the way she is.
我很乐意满足他人的需求
I like to give people what they want.
薇拉  给我朋友来杯美酒
Vera, make my friend something sweet.
还是下次吧
I'll save it for when I need it.
你为何而来  玛丽莎
What do you want, Marissa?
埃里克・海勒还活着
Erik Heller's still alive.
意料之中
Of course.
还有那个女孩
And the girl.
你到底为什么来这里
Why are you here precisely?
我需要你
I need you.
需要我这个不中用的老家伙  真是受宠若惊
You need me? Little old me! I'm very flattered.
我需要你的聪明才智  亲爱的
I need your talents, darling.
我需要你帮我做点
I need you to do things
情报局不允许的事情
my agency will not let me do.
停
Stop!
重来
Again.
从头来
Start again.
细节决定成败  不是吗
The devil is in the details, isn't it?
解决那个女孩还是埃里克
It's the girl or Erik?
她就在摩洛哥
She is in Morocco.
你需要的都在信封里
It's all in the envelope.
埃里克就交给我吧
Let me worry about Erik.
要杀死她吗
Shall I kill her?
找到她就好
Just find her.
玛丽莎
Marissa.
她跟你预想的一样吗
Did she turn out as you hoped?
比我想的还要好
Better.
重来一遍
Once more.
再来一次
Again.
还告诉我许多
...and gave me lots of advices
关于如何花钱避税的建议
about how to spend these money do these taxes.
虽然她很漂亮
You see even though she is beautiful,
但还是很会精打细算
she is actually brilliant with money.
别碰我
Get off.
比如有次纪念日  他说有1万5千块
Like for one of the anniversary, he said his 15 grand,
是买个爱马仕凯莉包还是做个隆胸手术呢
for a Hermes kelly bag or a boob job.
而她却知道
Now she said she knew that the
乳房假体每十年就要更换一次
boob implant will have to be replaced every 10 years.
而爱马仕凯莉包可是永不贬值
But that the Hermes kelly bag never depreciates in value.
隆胸就说到这儿吧
That's enough for the boob job.
可不是谁都懂这些的
I mean that's not just common sense.
所以我才喜欢她
And that's why I really love her.
我妈反对整形
Mum is against plastic surgery.
-没错  -甚至连化妆都很少
- I am. - Mum doesn't even wear make-up.
对  我觉得那很虚伪
I don't. I think it's dishonest.
这就是我的样子  不喜欢拉倒
This is my face, take it or leave it.
如果你学过美术史和人类学的话
If you study History of Art, Anthropology...
瑞秋是剑桥的优等生
Rachel got a first at Cambridge.
你就会学到红唇能刺激性欲
you'll learn that red lipstick mimics arousal
且能使人联想起小阴唇的形状
and suggests the geography of the labia minora.
-恶心  -而我的嘴唇红得很自然
- Puke! - Where as I have a lot of natural red pigments
所以我根本不需要涂口红
in my lips and so I really don't need it.
-太恶心了  -索菲
- Vomitory - Sophie!
-真难为情  -别老跟个孩子似的好吗
- It's embarrassing. - Just grow up! All right?
-别跟个孩子似的  -对
- Grow up? - Yeah
可是昨天妈妈还让我
Oh, because yesterday mum was saying
别像个小大人似的
how I shouldn't act beyond my years.
她确实被弄糊涂了  亲爱的
No, it does leave her with mixed messages, darling.
因为咱们都想告诉她
Because we're trying to
如何过个快乐的童年
communicate to her how to enjoy childhood.
我只想让她别再说恶心
I just want her to stop saying vomitory, all right?
这可不好笑
Oi, It's not funny.
汉娜  汉娜
So, Hanna. Hanna?
我很佩服你这么小就独自旅行
I'm quite impressed about you traveling around on your own.
我父亲鼓励我学会自立
My father encourages me to be independent.
真不错
You see, that's wonderful.
我在你这年纪的时候也是个背包客
I was back packing at your age.
那你父亲人呢
And where is he, your father?
我花了整整一个美妙的夏天环游希腊
I spent a heavenly summer, just island hopping around Greece.
环游希腊
Island hopping around Greece!
怎么了  挺好的  真的
What? No. It's valuable.
不同的阅历造就了不同的人
Our experience makes us who we are.
对吗  孩子们
Isn't that right, kids?
汉娜  你父母还在一起吗
So Hanna, is your mum and dad still together?
我母亲去世了
My mother is dead.
瞧你问的  老爸
Nice one, dad!
真替你难过  我母亲也在我小时候就去世了
I'm sorry to hear that. I lost my mum when I was very young, so...
没关系  很久以前的事了
It's all right. It happened a long time ago.
汉娜
Hanna,
你妈妈怎么去世的
what did your mum die of?
三发子弹
Three bullets.
天呐  太可怕了
Oh my god, That's appalling!
声音的组合
Combination of sounds
一种表达美
with a view to beauty of form
和思想感情的艺术
and expression of emotion..
检验报告
异常
"Abnormal."
万一下雨了呢
What happen if it rains?
那你就要淋湿了呗
Well, you going to get wet. Aren't you?
因为天窗被人打破了
Because someone broke the sunroof.
-你妈和我  -是你父母
- The thing is me and your mother are... - Your mother and I...
你妈和我  你父母
The thing is me and your mother, your mother and I
都是成年人  不像你们俩
are responsible adults... not as you two.
我的指甲又感染了
My fungus nail infection's back.
你是谁
Who are you?
你们找那个女孩干什么
What do you want from the girl?
我是她的舅舅
I am her uncle.
我们都很担心她
We are very concerned about her.
我不知道你到底要找什么
I don't know what you're looking for.
她来过  很友善  然后就离开了
She came, she was nice, she left.
说对了
Bingo!
可不是嘛
Voila!
车上的人已经结账走了吗
The van has checked out?
今天刚走
Today.
往北还是往南去了
North or south?
去渡口了  他们要坐渡轮去西班牙
The ferry. They caugh the ferry to Spain.
借你的笔用一下行吗
Can you lend me your pen?
我已经联系了国际刑警
I've contacted Interpol.
谁给你的权利
On whose authority?
沃特  我们不能再隐瞒下去了
Walt. We can't keep this to ourselves anymore.
-你没听我说吗  -他杀了两个警察
- Were you not listening? - He killed two policemen.
情况变复杂了  我们已无法控制
He's reframed the situation. It is out of our control.
那就让一切重回掌控之中  路易斯先生
Then we must regain control, Mr. Lewis.
除了我没人能再见到埃里克・海勒
I am the first and the last person Erik Heller will see.
懂了吗
Are we clear?
你听懂了吗
-路易斯先生  -遵命
- Mr. Lewis? - Yes, madam.
巫婆死了
天呐  你怎么在这里
Oh, my god! What are you doing here?
天窗是你打破的吧
The sunroof, was it you?
我是不是不该这么做
Would it be very bad if it was?
也就是说你一直都在我们的车上
You mean you were in the van, the whole time?
要是我爸知道了一定会犯心脏病的
My dad would have a heart attack if he found out.
-你会告诉他吗  -汉娜  你疯了吗
- Will you have to tell him? - Hanna, you are so mental!
我当然不会告诉他
Of course I'm not going to tell him.
我觉得你很厉害
I think it's brilliant.
-那你有地方待吗  -没有
- Have you got anywhere to stay? - No.
现在有了  你可以跟我待在一起
Yes, you do. You're staying with me.
可以吗
I am?
当然可以
Yeah, obviously.
我可以把你藏起来  但你得答应我一个条件
I'm sneaking you in, on one condition.
什么条件
What?
那些西班牙男孩  帅极了
These boys. Spanish. Gorgeous.
不  别回头  他们像球员一样皮肤健康
No, don't look. Don't go all pruny about it, like footballers.
也没有修眉什么的
Haven't got their eyebrows waxed, or anything!
-好  -总之我们今晚要出去玩  你也来
- Good. - Anyway, we're going out tonight and you have to come.
-好吧  -天呐  你真好说话  疯丫头
- All right. -God, you're not hard to convince! Perv.
什么
Who?
你有什么衣服穿吗
Have you got anything to wear?
你可不能穿这个  看起来像个德国疯子
You can't wear those, you look like some mad German.
害怕吗
Are you scared?
有什么可怕的
Of what?
我们现在要接吻吗
Are we going to kiss now?
你愿意吗
Would you like to?
接吻会带动34块面部肌肉
Kissing requires a total of 34 facial muscles
以及112块肢体肌肉
and 112 postural muscles.
而其中起主导作用的是
The most important muscle involved
口轮匝肌
is the orbicularis oris muscle,
因为要靠它来噘起嘴唇
because it is used to pucker the lips.
汉娜  你这个疯子
Hanna, you mentalist!
跟你朋友说  我就是想吻她一下
Please tell your friend I wanted just a kiss.
汉娜
Hanna!
-我该放开他吗  -不然你以为呢
- Should I let him go? - As opposed to what?
当然  快放开他
Yes, you should let him go!
我要走了
I'm going to go now.
好
Okay.
今晚很美好
It was nice.
是你吗  索菲
Sophie, is that you?
是睡魔来了
It is the sandman.
继续睡吧
Go to sleep.
天呐  你跟个土匪似的  真丢人
Oh, my god. You acted like a bandit. It's embarrassing.
-我怎么了  -我真服你了
- Like what? - Oh, I can't believe you.
喂  妈妈
Hello, mama.
我知道你对我很失望
I know you're disappointed in me.
我懂  抱歉  妈妈
I know it. I am very sorry, Mama.
但是  我也许找到了一个好办法
But... But maybe I've found a way to make it better.
我参与了一个项目
I'm in a programme now.
一个让婴儿更强壮的项目
A programme to make babies stronger.
是个美国的项目  很科...
It's an American programme, very scien...
你是怎么进来的  维格拉女士
How did you get into my house, Mrs. Wiegler?
我是来找埃里克的
I'm looking for Erik.
他说你已经死了
He said you were dead.
也就是说你见过他
So you've seen him?
他只捎过口信
He sent word.
汉娜在哪儿
Where is Hanna?
你没有过孩子吧
Did you ever have children of your own?
我有其他重要的事做
I made certain choices.
那你永远也无法体会
Then you will never understand
失去孩子的痛苦
what it is like to lose your child,
以及发生的一切
to not know what happened.
年复一年的漫长等待
The years of waiting,
无数次向窗外望去
of watching from the window.
静静地等待
And waiting...
等待
Waiting...
你见到她了吗
Have you seen her?
汉娜
Hanna!
她长什么样子呢
Can you tell me what she looks like?
跟她妈妈很像
Like her mother.
-汉娜  -什么事
- Hanna? - Yes.
你到底从哪儿来
Where do you really come from?
莱比锡城  我住在那里
Leipzig. I live in Leipzig.
如果我们是朋友的话
If we're going to be friends,
就应该坦诚相待
you're going to have to be honest with me.
这是规矩
Those are the rules.
-我们是朋友了吗  -是啊
- Are we friends? - Yes.
我挺喜欢你的
I like you.
有朋友真好
I'd like to have a friend.
虽然你疯疯癫癫的  但是我喜欢你
I mean, you're a freak and everything, but I like you.
我也喜欢你  真的
I like you too. I really do.
但是
But.
有些事情不能告诉你
There are things I can't tell you.
-你明白吗  -明白
- Do you understand? - Yes
其实不太明白
Actually, no, I don't.
有些人想要伤害我
There are peoples that want to harm me.
-一些坏人  -了解
- Bad peoples. - I see.
-他们会穷追不舍  -是啊
- And they won't stop. - Right.
所以为了你的安全着想
So, for your own safety.
那我们还是朋友吗
Can we still be friends?
不知道
I don't know.
我都不知道你到底是谁
I mean I don't really know who you are, do I?
本该如此
That's just it.
我都不了解自己
Neither do I.
-这是什么  -关于我的报告
- What is it? - It's something about me.
我知道DNA的意思  但别的就不懂了
I know what DNA means, but I don't understand the rest of it.
-你病了吗  -我觉得不是
- Are you sick? - I don't feel sick.
-你有什么毛病呢  -我没毛病
- What's wrong with you? - Nothing's wrong with me.
你接下来要干什么呢
What are you going to do?
我要去柏林
I'm going to Berlin.
我要去威廉・格林小屋和我父亲会合
I have to meet meet my father at the House of Wilhelm Grimm.
写格林童话的那个吗
From Grimms fairy tales?
没错
That's right.
既然你这么说
If you say so.
我又说错话了吗
Did I say the wrong thing again?
这个给你
Keep this.
别忘了我
To remember me.
这是代表友谊的手镯
It's a friendship bracelet.
谢谢你
Thank you.
汉娜在哪里
Where's Hanna?
你看上去糟透了  要不要喝点茶
Wow, you look rough! Do want some tea?
我喝过了  谁是汉娜
I had some. Who's Hanna?
在摩洛哥跟我们一起吃饭的女孩
The girl we ate dinner with in Morocco.
她在这  或说曾在  昨晚她和我一起出去
She's here, or was. She came out with me last night.
她怎么来的  跟她父亲一起吗
How did she get here? Is she with her father?
不是  她自己来的
No, she came on her own.
什么
What?
人们有自己教育孩子的方式
Look, other people have their own style of parenting.
他提倡独立性
He's promoting independence.
她像个孤儿一样  是我太保守了吧
She's like an orphan! Call me conservative.
-你真的很保守吗  亲爱的  -我才不是
- Are you really conservative, darling? - No, I'm not.
我说我们可以顺路带她去里昂
I said we'll give her a lift to Lyon.
我们下一站是去里昂吧
We are going to Lyon, aren't we?
我找到了早餐
I found breakfast.
好恶心啊
That's gross!
我们发现他了  我们发现海勒了
We've got him! We have Heller.
听到了吗  带他去见维格拉
Do you read me? Bring him to Wiegler.
她会安排审问
She will id an interview.
她是那样说的吗
Is that what she said?
两分钟前刚确认过
Confirmed with her two minutes ago.
玛丽莎  靠
Marissa, damn it!
在乡下我觉得很踏实
I feel so grounded in the countryside.
城市让我窒息
The city stifles me,
压抑着我的情绪  创造力和精神
emotionally, creatively, spiritually.
这样的地方让我们更接近上帝
Places like this bring us closer to God.
上帝
God?
不是很现代的感觉
Well, not any modernistic sense.
佛祖  克利须那  我们的上帝
Buddha, Krishna, the God within.
克利须那是印度教的神祗
无论你信仰什么
Whatever you believe in.
你有信仰吗  汉娜
What do you believe in, Hanna?
没有
Nothing.
你没事吧
Everything alright?
我想是的
I think so.
我不知道孩子是不是能听到我说话
I'm not sure if it's true that the baby can hear me,
但在夜晚我能感受到她
but at night I feel her.
我希望她能听到我说话
I hope she hears me.
你也曾有这样的感觉吗  妈妈
Was it like this for you, mama?
我想我知道她的样子
I think I know what she looks like.
当我闭上眼睛就能看到她
I can see her when I close my eyes.
我能听到她在我身体里  胎动
I can hear her inside me. Movings.
我是不是很傻  我想应该是个女孩
Do you think is that silly? Oh, I think it's a girl.
希望是
I hope so.
埃里克
Erik ...
怎么了
What?
老天  路易斯
Oh for Christ's sake, Lewis.
你好  玛丽莎
Hello, Marissa.
我听说你死了
I heard you were dead.
是你女儿告诉你的吗
Did your little girl tell you that?
-你在听什么  -自救
- What are you listening to? - Self help.
你需要帮助吗
Are you in need of help?
很高兴听你说话
It's good to hear you.
路易斯  派技术组
没想到我们还有机会说话
I didn't imagine we'd have the chance to talk.
你还没抓到她吧  你没那本事
You don't have her, do you? You're not that good.
埃里克  你真会调情
Oh, Erik! You're such a flirt.
技术组马上到
Tech's on the way.
你曾是个出色的特工  埃里克
You were a good agent, Erik.
看你现在这德行真让人心疼
Sad to see you go dumb.
我错过了什么
What did I miss?
我不能再这样做了
I couldn't do it anymore.
那些我们做过的事
The things we did.
约翰娜的事我很抱歉
I... I'm sorry with Johanna.
不止汉娜  还有所有那些人
With all of them. With Hanna.
为什么现在回来
So, why come back now?
技术组的人
Tech guys.
我问你呢  埃里克
I asked you a question, Erik?
埃里克  你还在吗
Erik, are you still there?
行动  出发
Move. Get up.
靠  靠  靠
Shit ... shit ... shit ...
汉娜  我想我们迷路了
Hanna, I think we're lost.
-我得靠边停下  -别这样做
- I have to pull over. - No, don't.
看不清地图
Can't see the map.
停下来了吧  我想撒尿
Have we stopped? I need to pee.
别走太远哦  宝贝
Don't want you going too far right now, love.
我觉得你还是别动的好  索菲
I think you should stay where you are, Sophie.
怎么了  汉娜
Hanna, what's going on?
稳住
Keep calm.
-我们到里昂了吗  -还没
- Are we are in Lyon? - No, we're not.
你想怎样都行  就是别跟着我
Whatever you do, don't follow me!
答应我别跟着我
Promise not to follow me.
我答应你
I promise.
谢谢你做我的朋友
Thank you for being my friend.
汉娜
Hanna!
行动
Come on, come on!
闭嘴  别说话
Silence! Shut up!
汉娜
Hanna.
太奇怪了  完全没道理
Definitely odd. Disconnected.
我觉得我和孩子关系不错
You know, I like to think that I have a rapport with kids.
我跟他们处得不错
You know, I get with them.
先生  这种时候
You know, sir, it's days like this
我尤其痛恨我的工作
that I really hate my job.
是啊  我懂
Yeah, I'm sure you do.
真的真的很难受
This is very, very difficult.
但有时候孩子们也不是好东西
But sometimes children are bad people too.
-别哭了  -我什么都不会告诉你
- Stop crying. - I'm not telling you anything!
-你认识这个男孩吗  -不认识
- Do you know this boy? - No!
他认识你  你的朋友很危险
He knows you. Your friend is in a lot of danger.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything!
她说自己住在莱比锡城
She said she lived in Leipzig.
就读于克劳斯学院文理中学
She went to The Klaus College Gymnazium.
她的朋友叫鲁迪和甘特
Her friends were Rudy and Gunter
她喜欢网球  有一只叫做特鲁迪的狗
She likes tennis and she has a dog named Trudy.
-她撒谎了  -显然
- She lied to you. - Absolutely.
她没有完全迷失
She is not lost.
但她需要照顾
But she needed taken care of.
我有东西给你看
I've got something to show you.
-母亲的照顾  -这就是汉娜的母亲
- A little help from mom. - This is Hanna's mother.
亲生母亲
Biological mother.
15年前  在一次野营中
15 years ago, she was shot to death
汉娜的爸爸枪杀了她
by Hanna's father on a camping trip.
想看看里面的东西吗
Don't you wanna see what's inside?
-说求你  -求你了
- Say "Please." - Please.
你是不是喜欢她
You like her, don't you?
没关系  我不会告诉任何人
It's okay. I won't tell anyone.
她很漂亮
She's very pretty.
-她在哪里  -这要你告诉我
- Where is she? - You tell me.
她有麻烦了吗
Is she in lots of trouble?
非常大的麻烦  亲爱的
The worst kind, sweetheart.
有些坏人在找她
Some very bad men are looking for her,
我要找到她  我想要保护她
and I need to find her. I wanna protect her.
你想让她受到伤害吗
Do you want her to get hurt?
不想
No.
她要去柏林  去威廉・格林小屋
She's going to Berlin. To Wilhelm Grimm's house.
去见她的爸爸
To meet her dad.
汉娜  是你  快进来
Hanna. Hanna ... Hanna come, come.
这边
This way.
等你了好久
Been waiting for you a long time.
埃里克是怎么跟你说我的
What did Erik told you about me?
威廉・格林小屋  斯提芬街
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Straβe,
21610559  柏林  德国
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
没错
That's it.
他没说过我的魔术吧
He didn't tell you of my magic.
克劳斯  09/05  周二见  埃里克
Klaus, 09/05. Be there Tuesday. Erik.
-是哪天  -就是今天啊  亲爱的
- What day is it? - It's today, my dear.
过来
Come, come.
坐这
Sit.
你饿了吧
Oh, you're hungry.
-华夫饼  -我能吃一个吗
- Waffles. - May I have one?
鸡蛋吗  当然可以
An egg? Of course.
你想吃什么都行  亲爱的
You can eat whatever you want, my dear.
我的鞋也行
My shoe!
我差点忘了
Oh, I've almost forgotten.
一个礼物
A present.
给我的
For me?
你需要张近照
You will need a fresh photograph.
不过都安排好了是吗
But everything's in order, yes?
为什么我要这张纸来告诉我自己的名字
Why do I need a piece of paper to tell me my name?
不是给你用的  亲爱的
Not you, not you, my dear.
但是我们其他人需要纸和电脑
But everyone else we need paper and computers,
这样我们就不用
so we don't have to ask people their names
当面问人们的名字了
to look them in the face.
你长得很好看
You have a good face.
你跟你爸爸长得一模一样
You look just like your father.
就连走路的姿势都像
And you walk like him too, uh uh uh.
我才不那样走路
I don't walk like that.
你就是这样走路的  亲爱的
Yes, you do! You do, my dear! Uh uh.
你也认识我妈妈吗
Did you know my mother too?
当然
Of course.
她是个歌手  出色的歌手
She was a singer. A wonderful singer.
你爱唱歌吗
Do you sing?
爸爸  埃里克没教我
Papa.. Erik, didn't teach me.
可怜的孩子
Oh, you poor child.
他还真是把世上的好东西
He has truely limited you from all the wonderful things
都跟你分开了
the world has to offer.
没有魔术
No magic.
没有音乐
No music.
我会教你的
I'll teach you.
是他来了吗
Is that him?
快到楼上去  亲爱的  快去
Upstairs with you, my dear. Quickly.
你好啊
Good day.
我们关门了  孩子们
We're closed, boys and girls.
埃里克在哪
Where is Erik?
他知道的不多
He doesn't know much
或者他很会撒谎
or he is a very good liar.
他认识约翰娜
He knew Johanna.
显然
Yes, of course.
还知道一点点项目的事
Bits and pieces about the programme.
对于女孩的事他都知道什么
What does he know about the girl?
他认为埃里克是她的父亲
He thinks Erik's the father.
-所有人都认为埃里克是她父亲  -真有趣
- Everybody thinks Erik's the father. - That's precious!
你好  我是玛丽莎・维格拉
Yes? This is Marissa Wiegler.
沃特  我没认出...
Walt, I didn't recog....
路易斯死了
Lewis is dead.
你不觉得这事应该告诉我们吗
Do you think it's important to tell us?
为什么还不告诉我们
Why didn't you call us yet?
抓一个人  只消一天时间
One man, one-day operation.
是啊  我们都想念路易斯
Yes. Yes. Yes! We all want Lewis.
他是被穿门而入的子弹打死的  沃特
He was shooting through the door, Walt.
不  我不会停下
No, I'm not standing down...
不  我有兴趣...
No, I'm interest..
好吧  是时候了
Well, yes. That is time.
听着  沃特
No, listen, Walt.
干扰
母体子宫DNA干扰
未经科学界准许
人体试验
伪科学
海辛格
Heizinger.
出发去外婆家  走
So off to grandmother's house, we go.
你见过她吗
Have you seen her?
汉娜
Hanna!
坐下
Sit down.
你是我的爸爸吗
Are you my father?
坐下  汉娜
Sit down, Hanna.
-你是我爸爸吗  -坐下吧
- Are you my father? - Please, sit.
是不是
Are you?
我当然是你父亲了  汉娜
Hanna, of course I'm your father.
-我养大了你  -可玛丽莎说
- I raised you. - But Marissa said ...
-汉娜  -别骗我
- Hanna! - Don't lie to me!
我是你的父亲  我一直陪着你长大
I'm your father. I've been with you your whole life.
把你当做亲生骨肉
Treated you like my own flesh and blood.
但我不是你的亲生骨肉
But I was not your flesh and blood.
-我是不是不正常  -不是
- I am abnormal? - No!
我在哪出生
Where was I born?
告诉我真相
Tell me the truth.
你在一所研究机构诞生
You were born in a research facility.
在波兰的农村  戈林加
In rural Poland, Galinki.
是什么样的研究
What was the research?
他们取出受精卵
They took fertilized embryos
对它们做一些小小的改进
and made small changes to them to improve them.
减少人的恐惧和同情心
To reduce the capacity for fear, for pity,
增强肌肉力量
to increase muscle strength,
强化感官  一切为了造就更强的战士
heightened senses. Anything to make a better soldier.
完美的战士
The perfect soldier.
我在一家堕胎诊所征募了你的妈妈
I've recruited your mother in an abortion clinic.
同样的  我还找了另外20个孕妇
I've recruited twenty women the same way.
-你是说还有其他孩子吗  -是的
- There were other children? - Yes.
在你两岁时
When you were two,
玛丽莎・维格拉终止了整个项目
Marissa Wiegler, she closed the whole programme
所有的研究
and all of this research,
全部废弃
it was disposed of.
懂了吗
Do you understand?
我爱你  汉娜  这点你要明白
I love you, Hanna. You have to know that.
因为我是个怪胎吗
Because I'm a freak?
不
No.
因为你是我的孩子
Because you are my child.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
别这样
Stop this.
让我走
Let me go!
别这样
Stop this.
汉娜  汉娜  求你了
Hanna! Hanna, please!
我一直在为你以后的生活做准备
I tried to prepare you for what your life'd be.
但你没教我该如何面对这事
You didn't prepare me for this.
快跑
Run!
搞定他
Take it.
你就这点本事吗
That's all you got?
跑啊  猪头
Run, pig!
为什么是现在  埃里克
Why now, Erik?
孩子长大了
Kids grow up.
格林先生
Mr. Grimm!
Mr. Grimm.
汉娜
Hanna
我在这  汉娜
I'm here, Hanna.
别担心  亲爱的
Oh, don't worry sweetheart.
站住  别再靠近我
Don't! Don't move any closer!
汉娜  我能帮你
Hanna, I can help you.
求你了
Please!
我不想再伤害任何人
I don't want to hurt anyone anymore..
我只是想聊聊
I just wanna talk.
结束了  玛丽莎
It's over now, Marissa.
让我走吧
Let me go.
汉娜
Hanna!
别想逃走  丫头
Don't walk away from me, young lady!
我没射中你的心脏
I just missed your heart
汉娜